

Fabio Soyama

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Graduated in Electrical Engineering, I was a co-founder of the Fenrir Team, an extension project focused on energy efficiency. I also participated in an exchange program at Hakuoh University, Japan, where I studied the Japanese language and gained intercultural and intersocial experience. I began my professional career as a Systems Analyst focused on SCADA systems, and I am currently working as a Full Stack Developer specializing in React, Nest, Golang, and AWS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, 4all - Hub de Tecnologia | Porto Alegre

JANUARY, 2023 - CURRENT

- Performed as a Full Stack Developer, working as part of an agile development team, focused on enhancing the user's online shopping experience (food, tickets, e-shop, etc.) through a digital marketplace.
- Work on developing new features, write tests, debugging and maintaining the digital product through dockerized microservices in Golang, Backend-for-Frontend in NestJS and Vite (React).
- Use AWS resources to deploy the infrastructure, watch logs and monitor performance metrics to ensure stability and scalability of the system.
- Constantly handle integrations with external services, partners and payment gateways, as well as contribute to building the entire architecture for new solutions.
- Main clients I have interacted with: major spanish football clubs, including
 Atlético de Madrid and Espanyol de Barcelona.

Novice Full Stack Developer, Agência Molla | São Paulo

SEPTEMBER, 2022 - JANUARY, 2023

- Worked as a Full Stack TypeScript software developer, building applications focused on Trade Marketing portals and advertising incentive campaigns.
- Developed the Front-End using React, with Hooks, Context API, and Tailwind, as well as Axios for API consumption.
- Built the Back-End with **Node**, developing RESTful JSON APIs and integrating with a PostgreSQL database using TypeORM.
- Utilized Docker to create containers and fully containerize the application using docker-compose and Dockerfle.
- Used **Swagger** for API documentation.

ICC Application Analyst, Alstom | São Paulo

SEPTEMBER, 2021 - SEPTEMBER, 2022

- Worked as a system integrator and configurator in IT, utilizing Alstom's
 product softwares, from architecture to data acquisition and supervision,
 in the railway signaling sector for projects such as ROCA Line (Buenos
 Aires), Line 2 of Santiago (Chile), and São Paulo Metro.
- Developed user interfaces for the control, supervision, and operation of metro-rail transportation for end customers.
- Extensive use of SQL, C#, Batch Script, and VB for database manipulation and configuration in SQL Server, as well as process automation.
- Familiar with **DevOps** culture and **Git**.

Internship and Systems Analyst, Siemens | São Paulo

DECEMBER, 2020 - AUGUST, 2022

Systems Analyst

- Worked on feld commissioning activities for electrical panels and automation systems in railway power supply substations for CPTM Lines 9, 10, and 11.
- Responsible for developing monitoring, supervision, control, and data acquisition (SCADA) software for the implemented systems.
- Interacted with client requirements regarding SCADA user interface systems and conducted training sessions for end-user operators to ensure proper system operation at CPTM's control center.

Internship

- Assisted in the development of electrical panels and auxiliary systems responsible for the automation and protection of substations and cabins for railway systems in the CPTM Line 9, 10, and 11 projects.
- Prepared and reviewed projects and documentation using AutoCAD.
- Developed a VBA-based tool to create an interface between Excel and AutoCAD, optimizing and automating internal processes.

FORMATION

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering, UNESP - Universidade Estadual Paulista Guaratinguetá - SP

2015 - 2021

2018-2019

Exchange Program, Hakuoh University | Oyama - Tochigi

DETAILS

São Paulo , Brazil
(11) 96418-3246
yuji.soyama@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>Github</u>

<u>Web Portfolio</u>

SKILLS

NestJS

React

Golang

Node

Microservices

RabbitMQ

gRPC

API Rest

SQL

Typescript

Amazon Web Se<u>rvices</u>

Tailwind Docker

Vite

VBA

Languages

English - Intermediate

Spanish - Intermediate

Japanese - Intermediate

Portuguese - Native